准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
美人鱼战士
和企鹅男孩
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
客串
配音  美人鱼战士
配音  企鹅男孩
美人鱼战士
Mermaid Man
敏捷又强大
Fleet and forceful
拥有集合海洋生物
with the ability to assemble
并使海洋生物向敌人发起冲锋的能力
and charge the creatures of the deep
赐予我海神王的力量
By the power of Neptune
美人鱼战士  还有他年轻的同伴
Mermaid Man, with his young associate
企鹅男孩
Barnacle Boy
为一切海洋生物而战
fights for all creatures that live in the sea
打击邪恶势力
against the forces of evil
不好
Oh, no
是汹涌漩涡
The raging whirlpool
美人鱼战士
Mermaid Man
深海的守护者
Champion of the deep
美人鱼战士和企鹅男孩
好耶
Yeah
深海的守护者
Champion of the deep
快  企鹅男孩
Come on, Barnacle Boy
邪恶落脚了
There's evil afoot
我的七鳃鳗啊  美人鱼战士
Leapin' lampreys, Mermaid Man
我就在你身后
I'm right behind you
美人鱼战士和企鹅男孩发现死敌
Mermaid Man and Barnacle Boy spot their arch enemy
反光怪  图谋不轨
Reflecto, up to no good
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
知道意味着什么吧
You know what this means
甜甜圈
Doughnuts
赐予我海神王的力量
By the power of Neptune
美人鱼战士和企鹅男孩合为一体
Mermaid Man and Barnacle Boy, unite
海底生物集合
Creatures of the deep assemble
使劲点  企鹅男孩
Think harder, Barnacle Boy
他们来了
Here they come
该死
Blast
反光怪力量太强大了
Reflecto has become too powerful
什么
What the
反光怪只要没晒到阳光
If Reflecto is cut off from sunlight
就会被削弱
he becomes weak
我的水母啊  美人鱼战士
Jumpin' jellyfish, Mermaid Man
他在破坏防护罩
He's destroying the shield
快  企鹅男孩
Quick, Barnacle Boy
回到海洋洞穴
back to the sea cave
好  美人鱼战士
Right, Mermaid Man
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
海绵宝宝  开门
SpongeBob, open up
反光怪发现我们的秘密实验室了
Reflecto has found our secret lab
真正的美人鱼战士会怎么办
What would the real Mermaid Man do?
你们要不然就自个去问人家好不
Why don't you ask him yourself?
说详细点  你这卑鄙小人
Elaborate, you vile fiend
他跟企鹅男孩就住在
He and Barnacle Boy live in
城对面的养老院里
the retirement home on the other side of town
他们肯定在执行卧底工作
They must be working undercover
对  现在求你们别来烦我
Yeah, now please leave me alone
美人鱼战士和企鹅男孩重新合为一体
Mermaid Man and Barnacle Boy, reunite
荫凉滩疗养院
辍学率飙升
全球海洋变暖
不好意思
Excuse me
我听说美人鱼战士在为重要任务
I know Mermaid Man is working undercover
执行卧底工作
on an important case
你觉得我们可以看一下他吗
but do you think we could see him?
卧底
Undercover?
好  我来查看一下他们能不能
Yeah, well, I'll see if they can
从忙碌日程当中抽空来看你们
take time from their busy schedule to see you
到了  他们就在那
Here they are, right over there
尽量不要太刺激到他们
Try not to surprise them
派大星
Patrick
你相信不
can you believe it?
美人鱼战士和企鹅男孩本人
Mermaid Man and Barnacle Boy in the flesh
塔塔酱
那些人谁啊
Who are those guys?
是来修电视的吗
Are they here to fix the TV?
你们想干什么
What do you want?
你们是美人鱼战士和企鹅男孩吗
Are you Mermaid Man and Barnacle Boy?
我们从前还是
Well, we used to be
但现在我们退休了
but now we're retired
可你们不能退休
But you can't retire
还有邪恶正在落脚
There's evil afoot
什么邪恶
What evil
邪恶
Evil
企鹅男孩
Barnacle Boy
不要忘记还有邪恶
Don't forget there's evil
我只是说还有邪恶正在落脚
All I said was there's evil afoot
邪恶
Evil
你能不能别说了
Would you please stop saying that
邪恶
Evil
耻辱
Disgrace
美人鱼战士和企鹅男孩
Mermaid Man and Barnacle Boy
真可惜他们老了
It's too bad they're old
你什么意思  派大星
What do you mean, Patrick
老人家最棒了
Old people are the greatest
他们充满着智慧与经验
They're full of wisdom and experience
这个世界需要美人鱼战士和企鹅男孩
The world needs Mermaid Man and Barnacle Boy
某个人  某个地方有了危险
Someone, somewhere is in trouble
不到美人鱼战士和企鹅男孩不再退休
and I won't rest until Mermaid Man and Barnacle Boy
我决不罢休
are out of retirement
好漂亮的光
Pretty lights
荫凉滩疗养院
前往肉糕
To the meatloaf
前往西兰花
To the broccoli
一定要给我的年轻孩子多打点西兰花
Make sure you give extra broccoli to my young ward
这位孩子很需要维生素
The boy needs his vitamins
给你  小朋友
Here you go, son
前往餐桌
To the table--
出发
away
小心点  不要乱跑
Careful, don't run
美人鱼战士
Hey, Mermaid Man
修电视的来了
Here comes the TV repairman
你想从我们这要什么
What do you want from us?
不要动
Hold on
让我看着你们
Just let me look at you
保持警惕  企鹅男孩
Stay alert, Barnacle Boy
他另有目的
He's up to something
能不能叫
Will you call --
能不能别叫我男孩了
Would you stop calling me boy?
你们记不记得
Do you remember
亚特兰蒂斯食物供给不足的时候吗
the time the food supply in Atlantis was running low?
于是你们发明了一把射线枪
So you invented a ray gun
这枪能让东西放大到原本大小的六倍
that made things grow six times their size
你们用这枪射海草园
to shoot at the kelp gardens
但是之后
But then
邪恶的射线恶魔突然袭击  把枪掳走
the evil man ray swoops down and swipes the gun away
并射向了所有海藻
and shoots all the algae
然后他附在海底穹顶上
And he gloms onto the undersea dome
他开始吸玻璃
and he starts sucking on the glass
你想表达什么  小朋友
What's your point, kid?
你们是史上最棒的英雄
You guys are the greatest heroes of all time
我觉得你们应该不再退休
And I think you should come out of retirement
听好了  你们这些恶棍
Listen up, you villains
我想吃我的肉糕
I want to eat my meatloaf
要是你们不出去
If you don't get out of here
我就用我身上的超能力
then by the power invested in me
宣布你们结为夫妻
I now pronounce you man and wife
里面这是怎么了
What is going on in here?
你可以亲新娘了
You may kiss the bride
你让我们的英雄重新合为一体了吗
Did you reunite our heroes?
没
No
但我结婚了
but I'm married
飞  飞  飞高高
Up, up and away
天啊
Oh, my
这个包真是又大又重
This purse is so big and heavy
不许动  大姐
Hold it right there, ma'am
我要把包抢走
I'll be taking that
救命
Help
奏效了
It's working
你是来救我的吗
Are you here to rescue little old me?
安静点
Pipe down
你会吵醒美人鱼战士的
You're going to wake Mermaid Man
一旦他被吵醒就会出岔子
and he's awry when his nap is disturbed
保持警惕
Ever alert
美人鱼战士练成了
Mermaid Man has trained himself
睁眼睡觉的能力
to sleep with his eye open
烦人精  离他远一点
Confounded, get away from him
别喊了
Stop shouting
我在午睡
I'm napping
不是我喊的  你这老不死的
It's not me, you old coot
什么事
Yes?
是我
That's me
我在这
I'm over here
不好意思
Excuse me
美人鱼战士
Mermaid Man
你想干什么
What do you want?
最好是好事
This better be good
这个肯定能让你们高兴
This will cheer you up
我们差不多已经
We're almost done
重新漆完了你们的无影船
painting your invisible boat mobile
本来应该无影的
It's supposed to be invisible
够了
That's it
我们的休闲时光必须结束了
We got to end our life of leisure
是时候不再退休了
It's time to come out of retirement
邪恶正在落脚了
There's evil afoot
邪恶
Evil
在哪
Where is it?
在那
There it is
知道意味着什么吧
Do you know what this means?
甜甜圈
Doughnuts
老天啊
Oh, brother
念咒语
Say the oath
美人鱼战士和企鹅男孩  合为一体
Mermaid Man and Barnacle Boy, unite
朝他扔水弹
Throw a water ball at him
水弹
Water balls
我的海鳗啊
Mumbling morays
根本没用  美人鱼战士
It's not working, Mermaid Man
他在吸收水弹  就像个邪恶海绵
He's absorbing it like some kind of evil sponge
狗刨
Dog paddle away
是汹涌漩涡
It's the raging whirlpool
你们这些恶魔
You fiends
他们还很享受
They're actually enjoying it
再来一遍
Do it again
现在怎么办  美人鱼战士
Now what, Mermaid Man
我们需要帮助
We need help
海底生物  联合
Sea creatures, unite
什么
What?
海洋生物好像
The creatures of the deep seemed to
不再光芒万丈了
have lost some of their luster
海底生物  进攻
Sea creatures, attack
掐我一把
Pinch me
我一定是在做梦
I must be dreaming
任务完成了  派大星
Mission accomplished, Patrick
对  我们成功了
Yeah, we did it
成功了
I did it
我感觉自己年轻了五岁
I feel five years younger
能回来的感觉真好
It's good to be back
我们成功了  你这老不死的
We did it, you old coot
你谁啊
Who are you?
美人鱼战士和企鹅男孩的全新冒险
The new adventures of Mermaid Man and Barnacle Boy
看我们的英雄斗智斗勇
We join our heroes locked in a battle of wits
砰
啪
将军
是海底电话
It's the aqua phone
什么事  首领
What is it, chief?
喂
Hello
挂
这电话还是坏的
That phone is still broken
记得提醒我去叫人修理
Remind me to get that fixed
坐
提醒你什么
Remind you what?
提醒我什么
Remind me of what?
我们的英雄会修好他们的电话吗
Will our heroes ever get their phone fixed?
下周继续收看
下周同一时间敬请关注
Tune in next week and find out
比旧版的节目还要好看
That was even better than the old show
全都是你的功劳
It's all thanks to you
眨
腌椰菜
分镜总监
分镜
翻译: 1440kHz
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
欢迎光临蟹堡王
Welcome to the Krusty Krab
我是章鱼哥
My name is Squidward
我能为你点餐吗
Can I take your order?
菜单
我要来份
I'll have a
不
No
不然
Maybe
不
No
我要来份
I'll have
不
No
那就
Well maybe--
你还点不点餐了  先生
Are you planning on ordering today, sir?
我要来份蟹黄堡
I'll have a Krabby Patty
好有独创性
How original
多加洋葱
And with extra onions
想法很大胆  对吧
Daring today, aren't we?
一份蟹黄堡  多加洋葱
One Krabby Patty, extra onions
一份呼喊强尼马上来
One crying johnny coming up
先放面包
First bun
然后肉饼
then patty
番茄酱跟上去
followed by ketchup
芥末
mustard
腌椰菜
pickles
多加洋葱
extra onions
生菜
lettuce
奶酪
cheese
番茄
tomatoes
面包  按顺序摆好
and bun in that order
呼喊强尼做好了
One crying johnny up
随你便
Whatever
十二份加小麦面包的蟹黄堡
Twelve Krabby Patties on wheat buns
面包肉饼番茄酱番茄面包
Bun, patty, ketchup, tomato, bun
一打呼喊农场奶牛
One dozen crying cows on the farm
好了
up
谢了  农夫布朗
Thanks, Farmer Brown
能服务你让我好兴奋
It's been a thrill serving you
能加点盐吗
Can I get some extra salt?
全用光了
We're all out
你可以去看一下吗
Could you check?
不行
No
让我猜猜  小不点
Let me guess, Tiny
你要一小份沙拉
A small salad?
我要来份双层三重全牛豪华堡
I'll take a Double Triple Bossy Deluxe
烤面包当底
on a raft
四轮驱动巨无霸
four-by-four, animal-style
多加带状疱疹  再摇一摇挤一挤
extra shingles with a shimmy and a squeeze
少加润滑油  让它哭
light axle grease, make it cry
烧了它  让它在水里游
burn it and let it swim
我们这是卖饭的  先生
We serve food here, sir
已经做好了  章鱼哥
I got it already, Squidward
海霸王
Bubble Bass
海绵宝宝
SquarePants
我听说你很会做蟹黄堡
I hear talk you make a mean Krabby Patty
对
Yep
我听说你很挑剔
I hear talk you're kind of picky
对
Yep
那么
Well, then
你拿去吧
here you go
海霸王  觉得怎么样
Well, Bubble Bass, what do you think?
还挺好吃
This is pretty good
只有一个问题
Only one thing--
你忘加腌椰菜了
You forgot the pickles
不
No
就这还最好
The best there is?
我可不觉得
I don't think so
你输了
You lose
可是腌椰菜本来应该就在这的啊
But the pickles should be right where they always are
我记得我放了
I know I put them on
腌椰菜哪去了
Where are those pickles?
腌椰菜
Pickles
你们得退我两块钱
I believe you owe me two bucks
两块钱
Two bucks
你们的承诺
Your guarantee
退款保证
那个啊
Oh, that
就不能再商量下吗
Well, can we talk about this?
不能
No
要不要卫生间代币折扣
How about a discount on restroom tokens?
免费
Free
来杯免费的水怎么样
How about a free glass of water?
一打免费的水
A dozen free glasses of water
我还加了冰块
I'll even put ice in it
别  回来
No, come back
两块钱  两块钱
Two dollars, two dollars
不  不
No, no
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
我记得往蟹黄堡里加腌椰菜了啊
I know I put pickles on that Krabby Patty
那两块钱从你工资里面扣
That two bucks is coming out of your paycheck
等等
Wait
回去工作
Get back to work
还有单子要接
We got orders waiting
我要来份蟹黄堡
I need a Krabby patty
好  这回我肯定不会搞砸
Okay, I am not going to blow it this time
我想想
Let's see
放面包
Bun down
然后番茄酱
then ketchup
然后芥末
then mustard
然后腌椰菜
then pickles--
那样不对
No, that's not right
放面包
Bun down
芥末
mustard
然后番茄酱
then ketchup
生菜
lettuce
再腌椰菜
then the pickles--
不对
No
放芥末
Mustard down
面包
bun
肉饼要放哪
Where does the patty go?
腌椰菜
Pickles
番茄酱
ketchup
等等
wait
想啊  想啊
Think, think
烦死我了
I'm losing it
放面包
Bun down
鞋
shoe
芥末
mustard
锅
pan
面包
bun
不对
No
蟹老板  我好混乱
Mr. Krabs, I am so confused
我都不记得要怎么做事了
I can't remember how to do anything
那你后半天回去休息吧
Why don't you take the rest of the day off
不行  蟹老板
Oh, no, Mr. Krabs
谁来做蟹黄堡
Who will make the Krabby Patties?
那个不用担心
Don't worry about that
有章鱼哥在
We got Squidward
什么
What?
蟹老板说得对
Mr. Krabs is right
我需要让我清醒一下
I need to get my head straight
是不是面包
Now is it bun
肉饼
patty
番茄酱
ketchup
大门  大门
The door, the door
蟹老板  大门不见了
Mr. Krabs, the front door is missing
对不起  蟹老板
Sorry about that Mr. Krabs
腌椰菜的事情害得我头昏脑胀
This pickle thing has got my head all messed up
我最好回家让我脑子休息一下
I better get on home and rest my brain
我家要往哪走
Which way do I live?
那当然
Of course
不对
No, no
是不是  面包肉饼面包
was it bun, patty, bun?
我想想
Let's see
番茄腌椰菜面包
Tomato, pickle, bun?
不对
No
面包  不对
Bun, no
面包
Bun
不对  鞋子
No, shoe
我好混乱
I am so confused
好好睡一晚上
Maybe a good night's sleep
估计能帮我让头脑清醒过来
will help me get my head on straight
是不是床垫床垫被单枕头
Was it mattress, mattress, sheets, pillow
再海绵宝宝
then SpongeBob
想啊  海绵宝宝
Think, Sponge
对了
Oh, yeah
是床垫海绵宝宝床垫
It was mattress, SpongeBob, mattress
再被单枕头
then sheets, pillow
晚安  小蜗
Goodnight, Gary
这样不对
No, this isn't right
晚安  小蜗
Goodnight, Gary
等等  这样还是不对
Wait, this isn't right, either
不对
Nope
错了
Negative
快啊快啊  给我弄对
Come on, come on, get it right
错了  错了
Wrong, wrong
错
Wrong
不对
Nope
不行
Naw
否定
Negatory
差点就成了
I almost had it
真是的  闹钟
Come on, clock
得怎么把这玩意关掉
How do I turn this thing off?
想啊
Think
小蜗
Gary
蟹堡王
蟹黄堡做好了
Patties are done
他把我蟹黄堡烤焦了
He burnt my Krabby Patty
他把我薯条烤焦了
He burnt my fries
他把我奶昔烤焦了
He burnt my shake
不  回来
No, come back
别  别
No, no
我必须要让海绵宝宝回来
I got to get SpongeBob back
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
SpongeBob
蟹老板好
Mr. Krabs, hello
真是会幸
Do you how do?
你这是在说什么怪话
Why are you talking funny, man?
我都办什么事不好
I anything can't do right
自从因为腌椰菜开始
since because pickles
胡说
Nonsense
你迟早会像你原来那样
You'll be back making Krabby Patties
回来做蟹黄堡的
like your old self in no time
我还没做好回去上班的准备  蟹老板
I think don't ready back to go to work, Mr. Krabs
你能行的  我的小子
Well, you're fine, me boy
好像现在不能行
Well, maybe not
只要找回你的信心就行
All we need to do is get your confidence back
这样你就能帮我多赚钱
So you can make me more money
我是说  做蟹黄堡
I mean, patties
我怎么办要
I how do that?
就像骑自行车那样
It's like riding a bike
你绝对忘不掉
You never forget
我会帮你的
I'm going to help you
只要你重新学会做蟹黄堡
You learn to make your Krabby Patty again
你的生活就会回归正常了
you'll life will be back in order
蟹老板  我不清楚我还
Mr. Krabs, I don't know if I
慢慢来
Take your time
不
No
我弄明白了
I got it
事情全都清楚了  蟹老板
It's all very clear to me now, Mr. Krabs
真的
It is?
对  我总算明白了我做不到
Yes, I finally realize that I can't do it
我做不到  蟹老板
I can't do it, Mr. Krabs
我是个废物
I'm a failure
别这么说
Don't talk like that
你不明白吗  你这硬壳小气鬼
Don't you get it, you crustaceous cheapskate--
我就是做不好加全套配料的
I can't make a double Krabby Patty
双层蟹黄堡
with the work
我根本不会把肉饼放面包上
I can't put a patty on a bun
再加上生菜
with lettuce
奶酪
cheese
洋葱
onions
番茄
tomatoes
番茄酱
ketchup
芥末酱
mustard
腌椰菜
pickles
还有顶上的面包  按顺序摆好
and top bun together in that order
时候到了
It's time
海绵宝宝回来了
SpongeBob's back
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
听说海绵宝宝回来了
I hear SquarePants is back
我就在这  海霸王
I'm right here, Bubble Bass
我还以为我把你赶出这座城了
I thought I ran you out of town
我属于这里
This is where I belong
给我来份老样子
Give me the regular
这一回
And this time
可别忘了加腌椰菜
don't forget the pickles
没忘
I didn't
还是没有腌椰菜
Still no pickles
看
See
恶心
Yuck
你又输了  废物宝宝
You failed again, SpongeBob-loser-pants
等一下
Wait a minute
看
Look
他一直都把腌椰菜藏在舌头底下
He's been hiding the pickles under his tongue the whole time
里头还有上次的腌椰菜
And there's the pickle from last time, too
还有我的车钥匙
And there's my car keys
还有我该溜了
And there's my ride
为我们的大厨海绵宝宝回归欢呼三声
Three cheers for the return
of our Mr. Fry Cook, SpongeBob
一二
Hip-hip--
万岁
Hooray
一二
Hip-hip--
万岁
Hooray
一二
Hip-hip
万岁
Hooray
为在我不在的时候
And three cheers for the fry cook
帮我代班的煎炸厨师章鱼哥欢呼三声
who took my place while I was gone, Squidward
一二
Hip-hip
去
Boo
一二
Hip-hip
去
Boo
蟹堡王
一二
Hip-hip
去
Boo
一二
Hip-hip
去
Boo
你就一垃圾
You stink